Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Katherine and this is our 300th lesson here at EnglishPod, so it's a special
我是Katherine，这是我们在EnglishPod的第300节课，所以这是一个特别的
lesson.
课程。
But today we're talking a little bit about dating.
但今天我们聊一聊约会的话题。
That's right.
没错。
Today we're going to talk about dating now in a little bit of a less conventional way,
今天我们要用一种不那么传统的方式来谈谈约会，
a new type of dating, very modern with using technology.
一种新型的约会方式，非常现代，利用了科技。
Using technology, that's right.
利用科技，没错。
So let's listen to today's dialogue and we'll be back in a moment.
那么让我们听听今天的对话，稍后再回来。
Do you want to hang out tomorrow?
你明天想出去玩吗？
Oh, I can't.
哦，我去不了。
I have a date.
我有个约会。
Really?
真的吗？
Wow.
哇。
With who?
和谁？
This girl I've been chatting with for the past couple of months.
这个女孩，我过去几个月一直在和她聊天。
She's really cool and she's driving over here this weekend.
她真的很酷，这周末会开车过来。
Wait a minute.
等等。
You mean you met her online?
你是说你在网上认识她的？
Yeah.
是啊。
I signed up for a website called match.com and it's great.
我注册了一个叫 match.com 的网站，挺不错的。
You fill in all your details and preferences, like if you are a smoker or if you have any
你填上所有个人资料和偏好，比如是否抽烟，或者有没有养
pets.
宠物。
Then you find people that have similar characteristics and you can email them or chat.
然后就能找到有相似特征的人，可以给他们发邮件或聊天。
That's kind of weird.
这有点奇怪。
What if she's a psycho or something like that?
万一她是个疯子之类的呢？
It's the same as meeting people anywhere and dating them.
这和在任何地方认识人然后约会是一样的。
I'm just tired of going to bars or being set up for dates by my friends.
我只是厌倦了去酒吧，或者被朋友安排相亲。
I think this is a really cool alternative, especially if you are a bit shy.
我觉得这是个很酷的选择，尤其是如果你有点害羞的话。
I guess it does seem logical.
我想这听起来确实挺合理的。
I'll have to check it out.
我得去看看。
All right.
好的。
We're back.
我们回来了。
Now, let's take a look at some of these key words that we've picked out for you on Language
现在，让我们来看看一些我们为你挑选的关键词，在“语言
Takeaway.
小课堂”环节。
Language Takeaway.
语言小课堂。
The first word is a word that you're going to hear English speakers say all the time,
第一个词是你经常听到英语母语者说的，
especially if they're Americans.
尤其是美国人。
Cool is our first word.
“酷”是我们的第一个词。
This guy described this girl that he is seeing as really cool.
这家伙说他正在约会的那个女孩真的很酷。
She's really cool.
她真的很酷。
What does that mean if I describe someone as a cool person?
如果我说某人是酷人，那是什么意思？
A cool person is someone who you like.
酷人就是你喜欢的人。
It's a good thing.
这是好事。
Someone who is cool, I think of as relaxed and interesting and someone who maybe has
我觉得酷的人，是那种放松、有趣，而且可能有很多想法或话要说的人。
lots of ideas or things to say.
有很多想法或话要说。
If you say that a person is cool, you're saying that you like that person.
如果你说一个人很酷，你就是在说你喜欢那个人。
What if you say something is cool, like Paris is really cool?
如果你说某样东西很酷，比如巴黎真的很酷呢？
Paris is cool.
巴黎很酷。
It's a cool city.
它是一个很酷的城市。
That means it's an interesting city.
那意味着它是一个有趣的城市。
It's something that you like.
它是你喜欢的东西。
Maybe you're trying to recommend someone to go there.
也许你是在试图推荐别人去那里。
You can also say that movie was really cool.
你也可以说那部电影真的很酷。
So again, it means you liked it.
所以再次说明，这意味着你喜欢它。
Yeah.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
So talking about dating, this friend was a bit surprised when he said that he met this
所以说到约会，这个朋友有点惊讶，当他说他是在网上遇到这个女孩的。
girl online.
在网上遇到这个女孩。
That's right.
没错。
So online, where is this place online?
那么在线，这个地方在线是在哪里？
It's in cyberspace.
它在网络空间里。
All right.
好的。
So online means on the internet.
所以在线就是指在互联网上。
And we often use this when describing things.
我们经常在描述事物时用到这个词。
So EnglishPod is an online English learning site.
所以EnglishPod是一个在线英语学习网站。
That's right.
没错。
So anything that is in the internet, in cyberspace, you say that is online.
所以任何在互联网上、在网络空间里的东西，你都说它是在线的。
So our website is online.
所以我们的网站是在线的。
Or maybe you have pictures online.
或者你可能有一些在线照片。
I have many photographs online.
我有很多在线照片。
Or I like to meet people online.
或者我喜欢在网上认识人。
Okay.
好的。
So continuing on, we talked about a website that obviously that's online where you find
那么继续，我们谈到了一个网站，显然那是在线的，你可以在上面找到
people and talking about preferences.
人并谈论偏好。
You mentioned that you can state whether you are a smoker or if you have pets.
你提到你可以说明自己是否吸烟或是否有宠物。
So what is a person that's a smoker?
那么吸烟的人是什么？
Well, many of you have probably heard the term to smoke before.
嗯，很多人可能以前听过“吸烟”这个词。
I smoke cigarettes.
我吸烟。
I smoke.
我抽烟。
But a smoker is a person who smokes cigarettes.
但吸烟者是指抽烟的人。
And so I could say that I want a non-smoker if I'm looking for a boyfriend.
所以如果我在找男朋友，我可以说我想要一个不抽烟的人。
Because I don't want someone who smokes.
因为我不想要一个抽烟的人。
But maybe if you do smoke, you can say I'm looking for a smoker, someone who does smoke.
但也许如果你抽烟，你可以说我在找一个抽烟的人，一个确实抽烟的人。
Okay.
好的。
So Jen was a little bit concerned saying, well, that's weird.
所以Jen有点担心地说，嗯，那很奇怪。
What if this girl is a psycho or something like that?
如果这个女孩是个疯子或类似的人怎么办？
All right.
好吧。
A psycho.
一个疯子。
Now, maybe you've heard of the movie Psycho.
现在，你可能听说过电影《惊魂记》。
But psycho is something that we use in English to say that someone is really crazy, almost
但“psycho”这个词在英语中用来形容某人非常疯狂，几乎是
scary crazy.
吓人的疯狂。
It comes from the word psychopath, right?
它来自“psychopath”这个词，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
And a psychopath is someone who is crazy but also very dangerous.
而“psychopath”是指既疯狂又非常危险的人。
Right.
对。
So obviously when we use this word, we're describing someone as being a little bit strange
所以很明显，当我们用这个词时，我们在描述某人有点奇怪
or maybe even a little bit dangerous.
或者甚至有点危险。
That's right.
没错。
So we don't want any psychos to come and talk to us online, right?
所以我们不希望任何疯子来网上和我们聊天，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
So he went on to explain how dating is just the same online as it is offline.
所以他继续解释，网上约会和线下约会其实是一样的。
And that he thinks it's a really cool alternative, even if you're shy.
而且他认为这是一个很酷的替代选择，即使你害羞也没关系。
So something is an alternative if you have different options.
所以“alternative”是指你有不同的选择。
Maybe dating by going to a bar and meeting someone is what normal people do.
也许去酒吧约会认识人是普通人做的事。
But an alternative to that would be dating online.
但替代方案就是网上约会。
That's right.
没错。
It's another option.
这是另一个选择。
So the word alternative is a second option, another option.
所以“alternative”这个词是第二个选择，另一个选择。
Right.
对。
For example, if I want to go have Italian food tonight, but you don't want to, I'd say,
例如，如果我今晚想吃意大利菜，但你不想，我会说，
Hey, Marco, well, can you give me an alternative idea?
嘿，Marco，你能给我一个替代的想法吗？
That is the other option.
那就是另一个选择。
All right.
好吧。
Great.
太好了。
So a lot of words in this very interesting dialogue.
所以这个非常有趣的对话里有很多单词。
Stay with us.
请继续收听。
We'll be right back where we'll take a look at Fluency Builder.
我们马上回来，看看“流利度构建”部分。
Do you want to hang out tomorrow?
你明天想出去玩吗？
Oh, I can't.
哦，我不能。
I have a date.
我有个约会。
Really?
真的吗？
Wow.
哇。
With who?
和谁？
This girl I've been chatting with for the past couple of months.
这个女孩，我过去几个月一直在和她聊天。
She's really cool.
她真的很酷。
And she's driving over here this weekend.
她这周末开车过来。
Wait a minute.
等等。
You mean you met her online?
你是说你在网上认识她的？
Yeah.
是的。
I signed up for a website called Match.com and it's great.
我注册了一个叫Match.com的网站，它很棒。
You fill in all your details and preferences, like if you are a smoker or if you have any
你填写所有你的详细信息和偏好，比如你是否抽烟或者有没有
pets.
宠物。
And then you find people that have similar characteristics and you can email them or
然后你找到有相似特征的人，你可以给他们发邮件或
chat.
聊天。
That's kind of weird.
这有点奇怪。
What if she's a psycho or something like that?
如果她是个疯子或类似的人怎么办？
It's the same as meeting people anywhere and dating them.
这和在任何地方认识人并约会是一样的。
I'm just tired of going to bars or being set up for dates by my friends.
我只是厌倦了去酒吧或者被朋友安排相亲。
I think this is a really cool alternative, especially if you are a bit shy.
我认为这是一个很酷的替代选择，特别是如果你有点害羞的话。
I guess it does seem logical.
我想这确实听起来合理。
I'll have to check it out.
我得去看看。
All right, we're back and we've picked out five key phrases for you.
好了，我们回来了，我们为你挑选了五个关键短语。
Let's check those out on Fluency Builder.
让我们在“流利度构建”部分看看这些。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建。
All right, the first phrase we've got here is one that we often use in English, spoken
好的，我们这里的第一个短语是英语口语中经常用来谈论见朋友的
English to talk about seeing our friends.
一个短语。
Okay, so the first person says, do you want to hang out tomorrow?
好的，所以第一个人说，你明天想出去玩吗？
To hang out.
出去玩。
That's right.
没错。
So let's hang out.
所以让我们出去玩。
We never hang out anymore.
我们再也不一起玩了。
What does that mean?
那是什么意思？
Well, to hang out is it's hard to define because you can do many things when you're hanging
嗯，“hang out”很难定义，因为当你出去玩时你可以做很多事情。
out.
但基本上它意味着朋友们在一起。
But basically it means friends being together.
所以看电影、听音乐、聊天，这些都是出去玩的例子。
So watching a movie, listening to music, chatting, these are all examples of hanging out.
所以也许如果你和朋友聚在一起，只是坐在客厅里聊天，你们就是在
So maybe if you get together with your friend, just sit in the living room and talk, you're
出去玩。
hanging out.
That's right.
没错。
Or you could go drive a car together and you're hanging out, you're talking.
或者你们可以一起开车出去，闲逛聊天。
So to hang out is to be social, is to talk to your friends.
所以“hang out”就是社交，和朋友聊天。
To spend time together.
一起度过时光。
And he said, wait, oh, I can't because I have a date.
然后他说，等等，哦，我去不了，因为我有约会。
Okay, to have a date.
好的，“have a date”。
So a date is a romantic appointment with someone that you want to go out with.
所以“date”是指和你想约出去的人的一次浪漫约会。
But you have a date.
但你有约会。
This is something you have.
这是你拥有的东西。
I have a date that night.
我那天晚上有个约会。
So this is actually a very important part because as you said, it's a romantic appointment.
所以这其实是很重要的一部分，因为就像你说的，这是一次浪漫的约会。
So if you have to go to the doctor and he's not your boyfriend or anything like this,
所以如果你要去看医生，而他不是你男朋友之类的，
you don't say I have a date with the doctor.
你不会说“我和医生有个约会”。
No, you say I have an appointment with the doctor.
不，你会说“我和医生有个预约”。
But if it's romantic, you say, oh, I want to get my hair done because I have a date
但如果是浪漫的，你会说，哦，我想去做头发，因为我今晚有约会。
tonight.
今晚。
Right, I have a date.
对，我有约会。
I want to look nice for my date.
我想为我的约会打扮得好看。
Okay.
好的。
And then he goes on to explain that this date that he has is with a girl that he has been
然后他接着解释，他这次约会对象是一个他一直在聊天的女孩。
chatting with.
聊天。
Okay, so the verb here is to chat with, chat.
好的，所以这里的动词是“chat with”，聊天。
Chat just means to talk to, but in internet terms, to chat with means to talk to on the
“Chat”只是指交谈，但在网络用语中，“chat with”是指在互联网上交谈。
internet.
互联网上。
So maybe you use a program like MSN or Google Gchat to talk to somebody online.
所以你可能用MSN或Google Gchat这样的程序和某人在线聊天。
That's called chatting.
那叫聊天。
That's right.
没错。
So I think everyone has done this at one point or another when you are online chatting via
所以我想每个人都或多或少做过这种事，当你在线通过MSN Messenger或任何这些聊天客户端聊天时。
MSN messenger or any of these chat clients.
MSN Messenger或任何这些聊天客户端。
So very, very common thing.
所以这是非常非常常见的事。
But remember to add the chat with.
但记得加上“chat with”。
I am chatting with my friends.
我正在和我的朋友聊天。
Yeah, I don't like to chat with people while I'm at work.
是啊，我不喜欢在工作时和人聊天。
Exactly.
没错。
On the internet.
在互联网上。
So now this guy explained about the website match.com and he said that he signed up for
所以现在这个人解释了关于match.com网站的事，他说他注册了这个网站。
this website.
注册了这个网站。
Okay, another really key verb when you're talking about internet things.
好的，另一个在谈论网络事物时非常关键的动词。
So for example, if you want to come to EnglishPod, you can sign up for a free trial.
所以例如，如果你想加入EnglishPod，你可以注册免费试用。
That means provide your information.
这意味着提供你的信息。
All right, start to use.
好的，开始使用。
That's right.
没错。
So it applies for things online and offline.
所以它适用于线上和线下的事物。
For example, in the real world or offline, you can sign up for a cooking class.
例如，在现实世界或线下，你可以报名参加烹饪课。
That's right.
没错。
Or last week, I signed up for a dance class so I can learn how to dance.
或者上周，我报名参加了一个舞蹈课，这样我就能学跳舞了。
Very good.
非常好。
Okay.
好的。
And then to finish off, the guy explained that he's tired of meeting people at bars
然后最后，这个人解释说，他厌倦了在酒吧认识人，或者他的朋友为他安排约会。
or that his friends set up dates for him.
为他安排约会。
Okay, so he doesn't like to be set up.
好的，所以他不喜欢被安排。
To be set up, remember that B. To be set up.
“To be set up”，记住那个B。“To be set up”。
It means someone else is doing this to you.
意思是别人为你做这件事。
So Marco, I want to set you up with my friend.
所以Marco，我想把你介绍给我的朋友。
That means I want to take you and my friend and make you have a date.
意思是我想把你和我的朋友撮合，让你们约会。
Right, exactly.
对，没错。
So this is exactly what it means.
所以这就是它的意思。
To set someone up or to be set up is to have them go on a date with someone else.
“To set someone up”或“to be set up”就是让他们和别人约会。
All right, so I don't like to be set up because I like to know the person I will have a date
好的，所以我不喜欢被安排，因为我喜欢在出去之前就认识要约会的人。
with before we go out.
在出去之前。
But when you're set up, someone else makes the decision for you.
但当你被安排时，别人替你做了决定。
That's right.
没错。
It's a little bit difficult.
这有点难。
That's right.
没错。
Okay, so a lot of interesting things here.
好的，这里有很多有趣的东西。
Why don't we take a look at our dialogue one last time and we'll be right back.
我们最后再看一遍对话，马上回来。
Do you want to hang out tomorrow?
你明天想一起出去玩吗？
Oh, I can't.
哦，我去不了。
I have a date.
我有约会。
Really?
真的吗？
Wow, with who?
哇，和谁？
This girl I've been chatting with for the past couple of months.
这个女孩，我过去几个月一直在和她聊天。
She's really cool and she's driving over here this weekend.
她真的很酷，这周末会开车过来。
Wait a minute.
等等。
You mean you met her online?
你是说你在网上认识她的？
Yeah, I signed up for a website called match.com and it's great.
是啊，我注册了一个叫match.com的网站，它很棒。
You fill in all your details and preferences, like if you are a smoker or if you have any
你填写所有你的详细信息和偏好，比如你是否吸烟或有没有宠物。
pets.
宠物。
Then you find people that have similar characteristics and you can email them or chat.
然后你找到有相似特征的人，你可以给他们发邮件或聊天。
That's kind of weird.
那有点奇怪。
What if she's a psycho or something like that?
万一她是个神经病或类似的人呢？
It's the same as meeting people anywhere and dating them.
这和在任何地方认识人然后约会是一样的。
I'm just tired of going to bars or being set up for dates by my friends.
我只是厌倦了去酒吧或者被朋友安排相亲。
I think this is a really cool alternative, especially if you are a bit shy.
我觉得这是一个很酷的选择，尤其是如果你有点害羞的话。
I guess it does seem logical.
我想这听起来确实有道理。
I'll have to check it out.
我得去看看。
All right, so talking about setting up, this is another word that comes to mind when your
好了，说到安排，另一个让我想到的词是当你
friends set you up for a date is a blind date.
朋友给你安排约会时，就是“盲约”。
Okay, so a blind date is not a date with two blind people.
好的，所以“盲约”不是指两个盲人约会。
A blind date is a date that you go to when you don't know who the other person is before
“盲约”是指你在去之前不知道对方是谁的约会，
you go.
在你出发之前。
That's right.
没错。
So my friend's mother loves to set people up on blind dates.
所以我朋友的妈妈特别喜欢给人安排盲约。
She's a matchmaker.
她是个媒人。
She makes couples.
她撮合情侣。
And so she will call one person and call the other person and then she'll make them have
所以她会先给一个人打电话，再给另一个人打电话，然后让他们
a date.
去约会。
She sets them up and then they have this date, a blind date.
她安排他们，然后他们就有了这次约会，一次盲约。
A blind date, that's right.
盲约，没错。
And actually what you're doing with this technology now that you can use a website to find and
实际上，你现在用这种技术，可以通过网站找到并
meet people who are also looking for romance, it's very interesting.
认识也在寻找浪漫的人，这非常有趣。
It's very modern obviously because now we have the technology to do it.
这显然很现代，因为我们现在有技术来做到这一点。
And many people actually have very successful or very great love stories of how they met
而且很多人确实有非常成功或美好的爱情故事，讲述他们如何
online, chatting or while playing a video game online or many different things like
在网上聊天、玩在线游戏或类似的事情中相遇，
this.
等等。
Well, the thing that I like about it, and I have to say I've never done it, so what
嗯，我喜欢它的一点——我得说我从来没试过——所以
I like from hearing about it is that like Match.com, you save a lot of time.
我从听说中喜欢的是，像Match.com这样的网站，你能省很多时间。
It seems that way.
看起来是这样。
Because you get to tell the person, hey, I don't like people who smoke.
因为你可以告诉对方，嘿，我不喜欢抽烟的人。
I don't like people who have pets, but I really like people who play video games.
我不喜欢养宠物的人，但我真的很喜欢玩电子游戏的人。
And so you find people who are like that and then you can get to know that person better.
所以你就找到这样的人，然后可以更好地了解他们。
But I think it's hard when you're going on dates, especially your friends, they set you
但我认为约会时很难，尤其是朋友给你
up and you have nothing in common.
安排，而你们毫无共同点。
You have no interests that are in common and that can be really frustrating.
你们没有共同的兴趣，这真的很令人沮丧。
So it seems like online dating is a new type of efficient way of dating because you preliminary
所以网上约会似乎是一种新型高效的约会方式，因为你事先
already filter out everyone or everything that you don't like about a person and you
已经过滤掉了你不喜欢的人或事，
find someone that has your same or similar likes.
然后找到和你有相同或相似喜好的人。
But that's modern day, right?
但这就是现代，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
A lot of people I know have dated using these websites and have been very successful.
我认识的很多人都用过这些网站约会，而且非常成功。
Really?
真的吗？
They've been married.
他们都结婚了。
Wow, it's amazing.
哇，太神奇了。
So actually this is a great thing.
所以这其实是一件很棒的事。
Let us know if you have any friend who's found their significant other, husband or wife via
如果你有朋友通过网上约会找到了他们的另一半、丈夫或妻子，请告诉我们，
online dating or if you've tried it, maybe you can let us know how it is.
或者如果你试过，也许可以让我们知道感觉如何。
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
我们的网站是EnglishPod.com。
Don't forget to sign up if you don't have an account and we'll see you there.
如果你还没有账号，别忘了注册，我们会在那里见。
All right.
好的。
Bye guys.
再见，各位。
Carmichael
卡迈克尔